Guide to the Chi Psi, Alpha Psi Chapter records, 1906-1965.
Chi Psi, Alpha Psi Chapter records, 1906-1965.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Chi Psi, Alpha Psi Chapter records, 1906-1965.
37-4-1124
Chi Psi. Alpha Psi Chapter.
1.8 cubic ft.
Annual reports, histories, correspondence, financial records, personnel records; pledging materials, and photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Annual reports; histories, including materials on the 1906 fire; correspondence; financial records; personnel records; pledging materials; and photographs of Chi Psi Fraternity.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Alpha Psi Chapter of Chi Psi Fraternity is located at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Annual reports; histories, including materials on the 1906 fire; correspondence; financial records; personnel records; pledging materials; and photographs of Chi Psi Fraternity.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Chi Psi. Alpha Psi Chapter.; Chi Psi--Fire, 1906.; Cornell University--Societies, etc.; Cornell University--Students.
Subjects:
Greek letter societies.; Students' societies.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to active members of Chi Psi or by permission of the Archivist.
CONTAINER LIST
- Chi Psi fire letters, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Chi Psi letters, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- The Calamity of Alpha Psi (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Chi Psi fire, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Chi Psi fire, December 7, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
- Chi Psi, 1908-1909 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Alpha reports, prior to 1930 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Alpha reports, 1930-1940 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Alpha reports, 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Alpha reports, 1950-1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Memorial plaque, 1944-1949 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Alpha history, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- [Charles] Love Durham Memorial, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- "Chaos Articles", 1941-1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- "Chaos Articles," miscellany, 1952-1958 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Thayer Trophy reports, 1952-1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Report of Alpha Psi to the Convention of Chi Psi Fraternity, 1952-1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- National Convention - Alpha Psi, September 1953 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Scholarship, 1954-1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- #1's position, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Alpha Psi historian, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Fraternity advisors, Cornell, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Student Medical Services, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Interfraternity Council (IFC) (Box 1, Folder 28)
- House operation, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Alpha history, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- 121, 122 Annual Convention reports, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- 122nd Convention, Paul E. Reading, Jr. '64, September 4-7, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Pledges - to be entered in #2's file (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Pledging file (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Pledge training (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Forms for pledges - past (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Past brothers (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Centennial History and Biographical Directory of the Chi Psi Fraternity, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Forms for pledges - past (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Employment file (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Cornell University faculty, officers, and employees (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
- Alpha Psi of Chi Psi - Local By-Laws; Parliamentary procedure manual (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Work details (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Duties of #1, #2, #3 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Alpha Management Manual (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Miscellany (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
- Finance miscellany (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Principles Underlying Sound Scholarship, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- The Purple and Gold, June 1895 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- The Purple and Gold, February 1904 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- The Purple and Gold, February 1907 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- 123rd Annual Convention, Chi Psi, Rutgers University - Alpha Rho of Chi Psi 85th Anniversary, September 3-5, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Records of the One Hundred Eighteenth Annual Convention of Chi Psi Fraternity, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Records of the One Hundred Nineteenth Annual Convention of Chi Psi Fraternity, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Records of the One Hundred Twentieth Annual Convention of Chi Psi Fraternity, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Records of the One Hundred Twenty-Second Annual Convention of Chi Psi Fraternity, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Records of the One Hundred Twenty-Third Annual Convention of Chi Psi Fraternity, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- The Cornell Fraternity Self-Study Program: A Report on Some Educational and Social Aspects of Fraternity Life at Cornell University, 1959-1960, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Photographs (Box 3)
- Blueprint: Chi Psi Lodge, 1965 (Map-case Folder 1)
- December 16, 1906 edition of Utica Saturday Globe with story and pictures of Chi Psi fire and deceased (Map-case Folder 1)
- Photographs, including several group portraits, aerial photo of Chi Psi house, medical staff of Harrisburg Hospital (February 13, 1923), unidentified portrait of a man with mustache (Map-case Folder 2)
- Photo of Sage Chapel with steeple and Chi Psi house in background (Map-case Folder 3)
- Panorama of Chi Psi Fraternity Centennial Convention in Schenectady, NY, May 1-4, 1941 (Map-case Folder 4)